Guide to the Kathy Acker Papers, 1972-1997 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series (Box 4)
  - Manuscript Drafts (Box 4)
    - Novels (Box 4)
      - Pussy, King of the Pirates (Box 5)
        - The Loneliness of the Weasel Cat. (Box 5)
        - The Point of Everything. What the Punk Boys Dream... (Box 5)
          Original 43-page corrected holograph manuscript in spiral-bound notebook.
        - In the Days of the Pirates. (Box 5)
          Original 50-page corrected holograph manuscript in 2 spiral-bound notebooks.
        - Dream Xtra. (Box 5)
          Original 60-page corrected holograph manuscript in spiral-bound notebook and the cover of a telephone owner's manual
        - In the Days of the Pirates (Pirate Island) O's Story Continues, Pirate Island. (Box 5)
          Original 55-page corrected holograph manuscript in spiral-bound notebook.
        - Virgin Gold Returns. (Box 5)
          Original 29-page corrected holograph manuscript in spiral-bound notebook.
        - The Creation of the Wor(l)d According to Dog. II Second Part of first draft of the end. (Box 5)
          Original 76-page corrected holograph manuscript in spiral-bound notebook.
        - Second part--final draft...p.1. Becoming a Rat. (Box 5)
          Original 47-page corrected holograph manuscript in spiral-bound notebook.
        - Dream Maps. (Box 5)
          Original 45-page corrected holograph manuscript (including original art work) in 2 spiral-bound notebooks.
        - Pussy. (Box 5)
          Original 158-page corrected holograph manuscript in 2 spiral-bound notebooks.
        - Ostracism, (Looking for a Pussycat) and After. (Box 5)
          Original 269-page corrected holograph manuscript in 6 spiral-bound notebooks.
        - Ostracism (Pussycat). (Box 5)
          Original 187-page corrected holograph manuscript in 3 spiral-bound notebooks.
        - Antigone. (Box 5)
          Original 168-page corrected holograph manuscript in 4 spiral-bound notebooks.
        - Preface. (Box 6)
          Original 216-page corrected holograph manuscript in 4 spiral-bound notebooks.
        - Games Love Chronicles of Pirates. (Box 6)
          Computer printout of: The Vision Passes (includes Playing House, p. 312-14; The True Colors of Piracy, pp. 315-20; The Vision Passes, p. 321-27; Becoming A Rat, pp. 301-10); The True Colors of Piracy, pp. 56-61; The Vision Passes, p. 62-68; Becoming A Rat, pp. 41-50; Titles [1 title pages from Pussy, King of the Pirates]; Playing House, p. 51-54; and Pirate Chronicles (includes Sections from The Chronicle of the Pirates and Pirate Chronicles).
          111-page typescript, heavily corrected by Acker in red ink. (computer printout and original typescript).
        - Pussy, King of the Pirates. (Box 6)
          111-page typescript with a few corrections by Acker. Containing: Preface: Once upon a time not long ago O, In the Days of Dreaming and In the Days of the Pirates. Clamped into red folding notebook.
        - Ostracism's Story. (Box 6)
          150-page typescript with a few corrections by Acker. Clamped into a blue folding notebook.
        - In the Days of the Pirates. (Box 6)
          67-page typescript with some original art. Clamped into blue folding notebook.
        - Pussy, King of the Pirates. (Box 7)
          Page 1-185 of corrected typescript. Page 185a-328 of corrected typescript.
    - Miscellaneous Drafts (Box 7)
      - Shorter Works and Miscellaneous (Box 7)
        - Address to the Author's Guild. (Box 7)
          10-page corrected typescript; plus 9-page fax of a slightly different version, with some corrections by Acker; plus 10-page clean copy; 2-page TLS concerning the address; another 10-page clean copy; plus computer printout of Author's Guild Speech (7 page clean copy and 1 page Speech Notes on Pirates).
        - Seeing Gender. (Box 7)
          Catalogue for the Pompidou Gender Show, Paris, October, 1995. 46-page holograph manuscript in spiral-bound notebook; plus 14 pages of original loose manuscript; 10-page typescript, heavily corrected by Acker, with additions and deletions, plus 11-page corrected typescript second version; 12-page clean typescript.
        - After the End of the Art World. For Art & Design., June 1995 (Box 7)
          14 pages of loose holograph manuscript; plus 7-page clean typescript.
        - Running Through the World. On the Art of Kiki Smith. For The Independent, London., March 1995 (Box 7)
          25 pages of original loose manuscript; plus 7-page corrected typescript, dated 2/95; 10 pages of typescript with some corrections; 8-page corrected typescript with 1 page of holograph corrections; 4-page TLS to The Independent giving corrections to the article; computer disk labeled Kiki Smith Cuntdisk Too(s).
        - Speech for Artist in Society Conference. Art Institute of Chicago., October 1994 (Box 7)
          4 pages of original loose manuscript; 7-page corrected typescript; 12-clean copy; various newspaper clippings of the conference; facsimile of the text of a proposed law on homosexuality in Idaho.
        - Miscellaneous writings before 1995. (Box 7)
          - Fucking Up Japanese. (Box 7)
            26 pages of a typescript.
          - The Language of Sex The Sex of Language. (Box 7)
            5-page typescript of an article for Marxism Today.
          - Christ Comes to New York City. (Box 7)
            1 page of a typescript
          - 21 pages of original loose notes for Wuthering Heights. (Box 7)
          - On Freedom and Democracy (The perverse position-political/sexual). (Box 7)
            19 pages of original loose manuscript
          - My Mother. (Box 7)
            19-page proof with corrections by Acker
          - Sade and Eugenie de Franval (Box 7)
            15-page typescript.
          - The Insoluble Problem of Violence. (Box 7)
            12 pages of a typescript with corrections; 1 piece of correspondence.
        - The Body Wetware. Canadian Journal of Political and Social Theory, 1993. (Box 7)
          15-page proof with title page and table of contents for the journal (Volume 16, Numbers 1-2, 3, 1993).
          - The Language of the Body. (Box 7)
        - Blood and Guts in High School Plus Two. Book Banning Documentation. (Box 7)
          18 pages of documentation from New Zealand on the banning of Blood and Guts in High School Plus Two.
        - Pussy, King of the Pirates. (Box 7)
          Compact disc recording by the Mekons with Kathy Acker. 2 copies.
- Correspondence (Box 7)
  - 1973-1978, undated (Box 8)
  - 1985-1993, undated (Box 8)
- Art Work (Box 8)
  - Original art work for Empire of the Senseless, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Folder 1 (Box 9)
      - 3 black and white drawings on large sheet (16.5 x 12 inches), with tissue overlay noting layout and reductions. (Box 9)
      - Tomomori with the anchor with which he drowned himself. (Box 9)
      - 9 x 12 inch ink drawing with red, silver and blue. (Box 9)
      - 9 x 12 inch pencil drawing (Box 9)
      - 4 (9 x 12 inch) black and white drawings (Box 9)
        - Discipline and Anarchy (Box 9)
        - My Family Fortune (with silver) (Box 9)
        - The Deep (with white and silver) (Box 9)
        - Dead Fish Fuck (with white and silver) (Box 9)
    - Folder 2 (Box 9)
      8 pages of Arabic script, pasted on art board, with notes on layout and reductions: six are approximately 8 x 13.5 inches; one is 7.5 x 6.5 inches; one is 6.5 x 3.5 inches.
  - Comic Book Strip for Dennis Cooper, 1 folder (Box 9)
    2 pages (9 x 12 inches) of original pen and ink drawings and calligraphy, in the form of a letter, signed by Acker.
  - Original art for In Memoriam to Identity, 1 folder (Box 9)
    - 4 (9 x 12 inch) black and white drawings (Box 9)
      - ...the path of life is but a dream (with silver) (Box 9)
      - How many dreams must we dream in search of real love? (with silver, white red and blue) (Box 9)
      - ...he sees two men who might not be real, fighting (with silver and red) (Box 9)
      - The fighter and the girl fucked (with silver, brown and red) (Box 9)
  - Original art work for Blood and Guts in High School (minus dream maps), 1 folder (Box 9)
    38 pages of layout with drawings and text, including 8 original black and white drawings; plus The Persian Poems by Janey Smith, 23-page original holograph manuscript. All are approximately 8.5 x 11.5 inches.
  - Art work for Blood and Guts in High School, 1 folder (Box 9)
    Color photocopies
  - From The Book of Correspondences and The Journals of Kathy Acker, 1 folder (Box 9)
  - From I Dreamt I Became a Nymphomaniac!: Imagining, 1 folder (Box 9)
    Negatives
  - From I Dreamt I Became a Nymphomaniac!: Imagining., 1 folder (Box 9)
    Layouts
  - From Pussy, King of the Pirates, 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Black and white photographs of Acker by Robert Mapplethorpe and Marcus Leatherdale., 1 folder (Box 9)
- Oversize Material (Box 9)
  - Art Work (Box 9)
    - Original art work for Pussy, King of the Pirates (Opaperfolder 1, Box 9)
    - Promotional poster for Blood and Guts in High School (Opaperfolder 1, Box 9)
    - Dream Map 2 from Blood and Guts in High School. (Framed-item 1, Box 9)
- Accession 2002-0081 (Box 9)
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Acker's writings (Box 1)
      - Sugar and Spice (Box 1)
      - William Burroughs (Box 1)
      - Moving Into Wonder (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Acker's writings (Box 2)
      - The Malady of Death (Box 2)
      - Pirate Island (Box 2)
      - Handwritten notebooks (Box 2)
        - Eurydice Seeing Visions (Box 2)
        - Eurydice in the Underworld (Box 2)
        - Orpheus in the Underworld (Box 2)
        - Eurydice's Monologue (Box 2)
        - Anglo-Saxon American Culture is a Culture of Shit (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Acker's writings (Box 3)
      - Eurydice in the Underworld (Box 3)
      - Pirates for the Mekons (Box 3)
      - The Destruction of the US/The Burning Bombing of America, [ca. 1972] (Box 3)
      - The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula #6: The Story of My Life, September 1973 (Box 3)
      - Two groupings of loose leaf paper (Box 3)
        - "commonsensival/philosophical use of words ..." (Box 3)
        - "I can't do just the dream shit ..." (Box 3)
    - Letters to Acker (Box 3)
    - Writings about Acker (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Acker's writings (Box 4)
      - Pussy, King of the Pirates (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Ackers' writings (Box 5)
      - Requiem (Box 5)
      - The Gift of Disease (Box 5)
      - Psyche's Journal (Box 5)
      - Handwritten notebooks (Box 5)
        - Eurydice Speaks (Box 5)
        - Notes: Leaving the World (Box 5)
        - The End of Poetry (Box 5)
        - Nice Girl, Gone Wrong (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Acker's writings (Box 6)
      - Handwritten notebooks (Box 6)
        - Ulysses Backward (Box 6)
        - Piece for World Art Class Notes (Box 6)
        - Girls on Earth (Box 6)
        - A Story by rattypussy ... (Box 6)
        - Late Afternoon. 15th, 5:00 pm (Box 6)
        - Nice Girl, Gone Wrong (Box 6)
        - Organs - Kidneys ... (Box 6)
        - Healing Journal (Box 6)
        - For the Jane Eyre Play (Box 6)
        - Listen, write down, what I like... (Box 6)
        - And after the land of death... (Box 6)
        - 20 years ago Dia G. was one of the high priestesses of Punk ... (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Acker's writings (Box 7)
      - Handwritten notebooks (Box 7)
        - Persephone Grow(n)up (Box 7)
        - Tales of Revolutionaries (Box 7)
        - Being in 1. Earth/Dirt (Box 7)
        - Psyche's Diary - 3rd taker (Box 7)
        - The Boy Raw ... (Box 7)
        - Make as real as possible ... (Box 7)
        - Raw Eurydice (Box 7)
        - Raw Daddy (Box 7)
        - Raw's Story (Box 7)
        - Raw Rat (Ismaiel) Dad ... (Box 7)
    - Virgil's Bucolica et Georgica (1963) with Acker's handwritten annotations (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (Box 7)
    - [Material removed from Box 3, folder Eurydice in the Underworld] (Opaperfolder 1, Box 7)
    - [Material removed from Box 4, folder New Gothic Fiction] (Opaperfolder 1, Box 7)